Let's see ... What were we going to talk about today ...
I forgot.
Ah! I remembered! we are going to talk about memories.
Recuerdos and memorias are synonyms.
They are two words that have the same meaning.
Memories also refers to a book: my grandfather is writing his memoirs.
So today we are going to talk about memories and memories.
Our memories are the only ones that allow us to return to the past.
And the thing is that going back to the past is impossible, there is no time machine -
Except with our memories.
And it's something we don't think about much.
That our memories allow us to return to the past.
So let's go back to the past. Right now.
What is your first memory?
What is the earliest memory you have?
Go as far back as you can in time.
What is the first thing you remember? Leave it to me in a comment.
In my case, my earliest memory dates back to when I was ...
Pf ... I don't know. How old could I be.
3? 3 years? Maybe?
2, 3 years? Something like that, I think it was around that age,
because I still used the baby carriage.
I don't know if I could walk, I think I could-
But I used the baby carriage and I didn't walk, I just sat.
So I was coming home sitting in the stroller,
and I think it was my grandmother who was pushing the cart-
and I remember that moment- which I do not know how I can remember, because I was just 2, 3 years old...
Really I do not know.
And suddenly I feel something on my foot,
like a tingling or something that was itching me a lot - I was itching,
and I was trying to scratch my foot - because it wouldn't go away, that tingling wouldn't go away.
I thought I had pebbles from playing in the park, inside my shoe.
So I tried to remove my shoe, but there was nothing.
And I kept scratching my foot: oh oh oh oh, it won't go away, this itch won't go away.
And I don't remember much else, that's all I remember.
Many times they tell us that our earliest memories ,
our most distant memories, are not ours.
But we have them because we see them in a photo,
or our mother, our father tells us.
They tell us: when you were little you did this.
And we think we remember it, but actually someone else has told us.
So here I present my next question:
Would you trust your memory?
Memories and recollections are very malleable,
very easy to distort and change.
And it doesn't even take another person to change our memories, to distort them.
They are distorted by something as simple as time.
Time makes our memories mold to our thoughts and perceptions of the world.
So even though I'm convinced of something, I don't know if I would trust myself.
Because I can be wrong.
I mean, I don't even remember the color of my murderer in Among Us,
to go around accusing: It was black! It was white!
No, I can't trust my memory. One cannot trust.
So, if you were given the option to have super memory,
would you have it or not?
And by having super memory I mean you can remember everything.
Everything, without making an effort. Everything that has happened in your life,
you just remember them. You don't forget it.
For some things it would be great, like for exams.
Imagine reading the book once and that's it.
You already remember everything.
You don't need to study, you don't have to study.
I remember everything.
That would be ... Wow. Where do I have to sign? I'm signing up, right?
But, I think it would also have its cons:
Imagine remembering everything that has happened in your life,
including the bad moments.
Imagine having to always live with the memory of a relative who has died.
Someone you loved very much.
Or imagine that you have to live for a long time with the memory
of the feelings you had for your ex boyfriend or for your ex girlfriend,
for your previous partner, those feelings of love, and never forget them.
It would be horrible, for that part it would be horrible.
This exists.
There are people who have this 'super power', but it is not a super power,
it's a disease called hyperthymesia.
According to the internet, people with hyperthymesia can remember
all the events that they have personally experienced in their life.
A person with hyperthymesia can be given a date
and they will describe all the events that occurred that day:
the weather and many trivial details that many people would not remember.
This is what hyperthymesic people can do.
I don't think there are many ... and obviously I've never met one.
But I wonder what it would be like to have hyperthymesia.
Do they consider it a good thing or a bad thing?
What do you think?
Do you think having a super memory is good or bad?
And then we also have the opposite of super memory and the ability to remember everything:
Not remembering anything at all.
I think this has no positive side,
unless your life is not good or you have done something very bad,
and you want to forget it, I think that apart from those times ...
Nobody would like to lose their memory,
and this is a much more common and well-known disease called Alzheimer's.
Families that have a member with Alzheimer's have a really hard time.
It is very painful for a person very close to you to lose all their memories.
And in fact this is a resource that many book writers use,
to create a dramatic moment:
When the protagonist forgets his friends, or his partner.
It is something that I would not wish on anyone.
Luckily, -I knock on wood- Do I have wood?
I don't have wood, I need to touch wood.
Well, I knock on wood, because no loved one or someone close to me can do that.
Please.
For all of this I would say that humans have the perfect balance.
We have memories.
We are able to remember many things that happen in our life.
But we don't remember everything.
We do not remember the answers for the exam ...
But we do not remember certain painful moments in our life either.
Because we have the ability to forget.
But at the same time we do not forget everything.
We remember one part and the other part we forget, and we have a balance ...
which I would say is correct.
I don't know if it's the best or the worst, but I think it's a good balance.
It's okay.
And that's it, up till hereTodo y Nada, episode number 2.
Now click here, and subscribe for more Spanish.
And if you don't feel like it then ... You should.
You should still subscribe.